（埃及 1938年）
（寻找阿卡曼拉法老之墓探险队）
Gentlemen，we are in danger。There is a storm coming.
先生们 我们危险了 风暴要来了
My men are terrified。We must leave.
我的手下都很惊慌 我们必须离开
That tomb is here somewhere。I can feel it.
那座坟墓就在附近 我能感觉到
Please，Robert，it's been two months！
拜托罗伯特 都两个月了还毫无所获
Archie，I'm not stopping！
阿奇 我不会半途而废的
Dad！
爸爸
What's going on with this wind，Pop？
这风是怎么回事 波普
C.J，go wait in the truck.
C.J 去车里等我
I don't want to just wait in the truck.
我不想在车里无所事事
I said go！Windows up！
我让你快去 把窗户关上
Robert！
罗伯特
Mr。Fredericks！What？
弗雷德里克斯先生 怎么了
Help！
救命
C.J？
C.J吗
Are you all right？
你还好吗
Yeah，I'm fine！
我没事
I'm coming down！
我下来了
Yes！
终于找到了
I looked for the tomb of Ahkmenrah for 20 years，
我找了阿卡曼拉法老之墓20年
and what do you do？
可你呢
You fall right into it！
你直接掉进了墓穴里
Amir，start loading the trucks.
埃米尔 开始装车
Mr。Fredericks…
弗雷德里克斯先生
there is no time.
没有时间了
The storm is almost upon us.
风暴将至
Then you'd better hurry.
那你最好动作快点
Come on。Everybody works.
快点 大家都动起来
Hey！What's the matter with you？Huh？
你是怎么回事
He said，「We must leave this place immediately.
他说 我们必须立刻离开
「If anyone disturbs this tomb…
如果有任何人打扰法老之墓的安宁
「The end will come.」
末日将至
We load the trucks.
我们装车
I can't help feeling we're making a terrible mistake！
我觉得我们在犯一个可怕的错误
We're not making a mistake，we're making history！
这不是犯错 这叫创造历史
Don't worry！
别担心
C.J！Let's go！
C.J 快走吧
「The end will come.」
末日将至
《博物馆奇妙夜3：墓葬秘密》
Welcome，everyone，to the Grand Reopening…
欢迎各位莅临自然历史博物馆
of the newly renovated Hayden Planetarium…
参加刚修缮完毕的海登天文馆
here at the Museum of Natural History.
盛大的重开仪式
New York's glitterati have all turned out…
纽约名流齐聚一堂
for what has promised to be a memorable evening…
这注定难忘的夜晚
filled with the dazzling special effects…
在让人眼花缭乱的特效
and technical wizardry.
和技术魔法中
We've all come to admire from this museum…
我们来到这里 欣赏博物馆
and its renowned Night Program.
欣赏著名的奇妙夜
Tonight gonna be fun-fun！
今晚不会闷闷
Here come Dum Dum！
大家欢迎笨笨
Hey，how we doing，Sac？
你好吗 萨卡
Rexy is waxed and buffed.
雷克斯打蜡抛光完毕
Teddy is grooming his moustache.
泰迪在整理他的小胡子
Oh，and I reviewed fire
我还给原始人
safety procedures with the primordial men.
复习了博物馆的消防安全规程
By the way，have you seen them lately？
对了 你们最近见过他们吗
The museum has added a new one.
博物馆新添了一个原始人
What？No.
什么 没有
Oh，and make sure the centurions stretch，all right？
要让百夫长把动作舒展开 好吗
They really went for it in the dress rehearsal…
他们在带妆彩排上很卖力
and they're just not used to those kinds of dance moves.
但确实还不太习惯这种舞步
Okay，everybody。Everybody，listen up.
好了 各位 听着
I don't want to make anybody nervous…
我不想让大家紧张
but the mayor and the governor are both out there.
但市长和州长都将观看演出
And，uh，I'm not 100 percent sure，
虽然我不是百分之百确定
but I think Regis Philbin，too.
但我想里吉斯·菲尔宾也会来
Reeju Philbo？
里吉·菲波
Yeah，Reeju Philbo.
对 里吉·菲波
Okay，Rexy，do me a favor.
雷克斯 拜托了
Watch the tail，okay？There's gonna be open flame.
小心尾巴 表演会有明火
Oh，Dexter…
德克斯特
how you doing，my man？
你好啊 哥们儿
All limbered up？
都准备好了吗
Looking good。I like the tie.
看上去不错 领结很棒
Got kind of a Chippendales thing going on.
有点齐本德尔风
All chalked up，ready to go？
防滑粉也涂了 准备好了吗
Good。Okay，everybody relax and have fun，okay？
很好 大家放松点 尽情享受吧
Larry.
拉里
You better come see this.
你最好过来看一下
Have you ever seen it like this before？
之前发生过这种情况吗
Never.
从来没有过
This corrosion has never happened before.
从来没见过它被腐蚀
It's always been exactly the same.
它以前从来都是一个样
I wonder what's up with it.
你说它怎么了呢
I have no idea.
不知道
And to be honest…
说实话
my father knew the secrets of the Tablet better than I did.
我父亲比我更了解金碑的秘密
Unfortunately，he swore he'd never reveal them.
可惜他发过誓 永远不透露这个秘密
He never did.
而且也真的只字未提
You okay？
你还好吧
Yes.
还好
Yes，I'm fine.
我没事
Just take it easy out there tonight，all right？
今晚表演不要紧张 好吗
You got 15 minutes till showtime.
你还有15分钟就要上台了
We're gonna figure this out tomorrow.
我们明天再考虑这件事
All right.
好的
Look at that！
快看
Doggone it！
我的妈呀
Did you see that？
你看到了吗
They're trying to catch the light.
它们想把光抓住
But you can't do it，boys！You can't catch light！
做不到的 小猫咪 光是抓不住的
It's as elusive as human happiness！
光和人类的幸福一样可望而不可及
I should like to comment.
我要评论
Summon the apparatus.
召唤装备
Summon the apparatus！
上装备
What are you gonna say？
你打算发什么
「Laugh out loud.」 Yeah，that's what I did.
笑翻了 对 我也这么缩写
Now，post these adorable kittens
现在把这个萌猫视频
with my edict of approval to Facebook.
和我的御评一起发到脸书去
Give a big Texas 「Hell yeah」
也代杰迪戴亚向脸书群众
from old Jedediah…
带去德克萨斯式喝彩
because I loved it too！
因为我也特爱这视频
Just send a smiley face.
发个笑脸就行了
Yeah，but with a wink！
要带眨眼的那个笑脸
A smiley face and a wink！
眨眼笑脸
Guys，what are you doing？
几位 你们干什么呢
We're just watching kittens.
就是看个萌猫视频
You're on in five minutes。You got to focus，here.
还有5分钟你们就要上台了 别分心
I told you we don't have time for this！
我跟你说不该在这儿浪费时间的
You gave it a Texas 「Hell yeah！」
你还发了德克萨斯式喝彩呢
Hey，Teddy，ready to roll？
泰迪 准备好了吗
Indeed，Lawrence.
当然 劳伦斯
- Great。- Battle of San Juan Hill…
- 很好 - 古巴圣胡安山之战时
cool as a cucumber.
我可是很冷静的
Right now，butterflies like you wouldn't believe.
但现在 心里小鹿乱撞 忐忑异常
You're gonna be great.
你会很棒的
Lawrence？
劳伦斯
Have you seen the Neanderthals lately？
你最近看到过穴居人吗
No。Why does everybody keep talking about this？
没有 怎么大家都这么关注
You may want to give it a look！
你会想去看看的
Hey，guys，what's going on？
伙计们 怎么了
All right，very funny.
好吧 真有趣
That's hilarious.
真好笑
It's alright，you don't have to come down.
没事 不必下来了
It's okay，really.
不用客气 真的
Hi，how are you？I'm Larry.
你好吗 我是拉里
I'm Laaa…
我是拉
You're 「Laaa」？
你是拉啊
Laaa.
拉
Laaa。Okay，nice to meet you，Laaa.
很高兴见到你 拉
Welcome aboard，and…
欢迎加入我们 然后
Yes，we look similar.
没错 我们长的很像
Yeah，we look like each other，I know.
我们非常相似 我知道
It's a joke that somebody played.
这肯定是谁开的玩笑
Dr。McPhee had you made to look like me.
麦克菲博士把你做成了我的模样
It's just a…
就是
Stop it。Stop，okay？
别这样 行吗
- Dada？- What？
- 爸比 - 怎么了
Dada.
爸比
No，not your Dada.
不 不是你爸比
Yeah，Dada.
爸比
- No。Stop。- Dada.
- 不 停下 - 爸比
- Dada！- Dada！
- 爸比 - 爸比
No，I'm not his… I'm not your Dada.
我不是他的 不是你爸比
Dum Dum got a new son-son！
笨笨又有宝宝啦
No，he doesn't.
不 他没有
Dada！
爸比
A toast to our new chairwoman.
为新任女议长干杯
Cheers，everyone。Cheers.
请大家举杯 干杯
Cue the music.
音乐响起
And Teddy in three，two…
泰迪倒计时开始 三 二
Since 1869，when I was a mere boy of 11…
1869年 我还是个11岁的男孩时
this museum has been a shining beacon to our great city.
博物馆就是这伟大城市中一颗耀眼明珠
Tonight we'll expand our horizons even further…
今天我们将让它的光芒传播到更远的地方
to the Sun…
到达太阳
the Moon，and the stars.
月亮 和渺渺星辰
From our very beginning…
开天辟地 混沌初开之时
mankind has looked to the heavens
人们就在仰望天空
and given names to what he saw，
命名着目之所及
the constellations.
这就是星座的由来
I thought you might like to meet them.
我想大家也许愿意见见这些星座
Cue the constellations.
星座特效开启
Orion，the hunter！
俄里翁 猎户星座
What？
怎么了
All planned。All planned.
都是计划好的
I knew that was gonna happen。So，yeah.
我早知道会这样的 没事没事
Good。Going great，guys。Going great.
很棒 进展顺利
Let's drop the silks.
放下丝绸
And go with the monkey.
猴子出场
What？
什么
Come on.
加油
That's what I do.
这是我应该做的
Thank you for your patronage…
感谢您的光临
and for your unwavering support of this fine institution.
感谢您对这个优秀机构的鼎力支持
This newly renovated planetarium will serve as a lens…
新近重开的天文馆就像一架望远镜
「Once more unto the breach，dear friends！」
共赴战场 我亲爱的朋友
What？
什么
Charge！
冲啊
Rough Riders！
骑兵们
- It's okay！Just hang on！- Is this part of it？
- 没事 稍安勿躁 - 这也是表演吗
Sorry folks，a little technical issue.
抱歉各位 出了点技术问题
What are you doing？
你在干什么
Stick to the script。Stick to the script！Huh？
按照剧本走 按照剧本走
- It's me！- I don't know you.
- 是我 - 我不认识你
Pull！
拉
I don't know what's come over me，but I like it！
我不知道我是怎么了 但感觉不错
Drop 'em！
放倒他们
What's going on？
怎么回事
Do something！
快想办法
What are you doing？
你在干什么
Orion，don't！
俄里翁 不要
Rexy！
雷克斯
Guys，what was going on out there？
伙计们 刚才是怎么回事
Seriously，what were you thinking？
说真的 你们怎么想的啊
Laaa，I got this，all right？
拉 我一个人就行
Just… go over there.
你去那边吧
No，go over there.
不 去那边
Go.
去吧
（点击器）
Attila…
匈奴王
what were you doing to that dolphin，man？
你对那只海豚做了什么
It's a dolphin！
那是只海豚哎
It's one of the most peaceful creatures on earth…
地球上最热爱和平的生物之一
and you're hacking into it like it was The Cove or something.
你却像《海豚湾》中日本人一样残杀它们
Did you see the look on Regis Philbin's face？
看到里吉斯·菲尔宾脸上表情没
Reeju？
你是说里吉
Yeah，Reeju.
对 里吉
Teddy，what were you doing pointing a gun at me？
泰迪 你为什么拿枪瞄着我
Forgive me，Lawrence。I don't know what came over me.
抱歉劳伦斯 我不知道我怎么了
Do you even remember that？
你还记得那些事吗
Not at all.
一点也不记得
Laaa，shut that down！It's a defibrillator.
拉 快关掉 那是个电击器
Put it down。It's dangerous！
快放下 很危险
Laaa，that's electricity。Those aren't headphones.
拉 那是电击 不是耳机
Stop it！What are you…
住手 你这是
Oh！Hey！Whoa！Dexter！
天哪 德克斯特
What are you doing？
你在干什么
Honestly，if you're gonna act like a baby，
你要是一直这么幼稚
then I'll get you some diapers.
我就去给你买点纸尿裤
You want diapers again？Huh？
又想穿纸尿裤了是不是
Ease up on the reins there，horse.
马儿 别激动
Can't you see？He feels terrible！
你看不到吗 他很愧疚了
Hell，we all do！
事实上 我们都很愧疚的
I don't know what's going on with everybody here…
我不知道大家这是怎么了
but tonight was really weird。Really weird.
但今晚真的很奇怪 真的
We feel awful.
我们很抱歉
Something took hold of us like an evil spell！
我们像被魔咒控制了一样
Yeah，like we just weren't ourselves.
对 我们都不像平常的自己了
- Hello？- Larry.
- 喂 - 拉里
Hey，Dr。McPhee.
麦克菲博士
Yeah，hi。How's it going？
你好 怎么样
Uh，okay.
还行吧
Good，good，good，good，good，good.
很好很好
You know that sound of when you're hiding in a trash bin…
你知道躲在垃圾桶里担心着小命不保
fearing for your life because
因为霸王龙雷克斯在把装着你的
a Tyrannosaurus rex is using it as a Hacky Sack？
垃圾桶当球踢时的那种声音吗
No。I don't know that sound.
我没有听过这种声音
You don't know that sound？Oh，hold on one second.
你没有听过啊 稍等
That's the sound！That's the sound！It will haunt my dreams！
就是这种声音 害的我觉也睡不好
I'm sorry。Look，really，I'm sorry.
我很抱歉 我真的很抱歉
I swear to you，I had no idea this was going to happen.
我发誓 我真的不知道今晚到底
「I had no idea it was gonna happen.
我不知道今晚怎么回事
「I'm only in charge of all the special effects.」
我只负责特效管理
It was your fault！They were your special effects！
这是你的错 特效是你负责的
- No，I know。- That's a joke.
- 不 我知道 - 真是笑话
「Special effects」？More like 「Special…
特效 还不如说是
「Defects！」
特烂
Look，I promise you，I'm gonna find out what happened.
我保证 我会弄清楚这是怎么回事
Or they were 「Special rejects！」
或者说他们就是 特次品
I'm sorry，Dr。McPhee。I gotta go.
抱歉 麦克菲博士 我得挂了
Nicky！Nicky！
尼基 尼基
Stop hopping！
别跳了
Dad，what are you doing？
爸爸 你干什么呀
What are you doing？
这话该我问你才对
It's 3 am.
都凌晨三点了
All right，party's over！
好了 聚会结束
Who are you？
你是谁
- I'm Sophie。- Sophie？
- 我叫Sophie - Sophie
The Bye Bye Birdie？
演《再见，伯蒂》那个吗
- Right。- It was good.
- 对 - 演得不错
- Thanks。- Yeah.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
See you tomorrow night？
那么明晚见
- Probably not。- Probably.
- 可能不行 - 可能行
Definitely not.
绝对不行
Bye.
拜
You're in so much trouble.
你摊上事儿了
I know.
我知道
I didn't really know you were coming home early.
我不知道你会提前回家
Yeah，that's pretty obvious.
嗯 这能看出来
I mean…
我说
what makes you think this is okay？
你怎么能这样
When I'm not at Mom's，
我不在妈妈那儿住的时候
you leave me alone，like，every night.
你每晚都扔我一个人在家
Look，you can't be doing this right now.
听着 你现在还不能这么放肆
You got finals，
你有期末考试
your NYU application is due in what，two weeks？
纽约大学的申请期限还有多久 两周吧
I'm not gonna get into NYU.
我不会去纽约大学
- You don't know that。- No，I do.
- 你不能确认 - 不 我确认
You don't know that.
你不能确认
I do very much know that，
我确认 非常确定
in the sense that I don't intend to apply.
因为我根本没想申请
What？
什么
I don't think that it's the place for me right now，Dad.
我觉得那个地方现在并不适合我 爸爸
Okay。All right，fine.
好吧 没事儿 也行
You want to spread your wings a little…
你想要自由飞翔
get out of the city，go to school somewhere else.
去别的城市 到其他地方念书
Ok。I totally support that.
行 我完全赞成
All you had to do was tell me.
你只需要事先告诉我就行了
So where do you want to go？
你想去哪
- What's the list？- It's a short list.
- 有候选名单吗 - 名单很短
Great。I like it。Focus.
很好 我喜欢 目标明确
I'mma hit you with a super short list，man，because it's…
我能给的名单很短 老爸 因为…
There's nothing on it.
名单上什么都没有
There's…
什么也没…
I'm confused，because there's not a list…
我不明白 什么叫没有名单
Dad？
爸爸
I want to take a year off.
我想休学一年
I would like to do exactly what you just said.
我就想照你刚才说的做
I want to spread my wings.
我想自由飞翔
You want to spread your wings，that's great.
你想自由飞翔 这很好
But you can't spread your wings and fly to nowhere.
但是你不能光张开翅膀哪儿也不去
- Plans change。- No，they don't.
- 计划有变 - 不 没变
No，they don't。Plans don't change.
不 没变 计划没变
We had a plan，it changed.
我们曾经有过计划 但它变了
- It's disorienting at first。- No.
- 一开始可能会不知所措 - 不
You can't change the plan…
你不能改变计划
unless you check with the people who are financing the plan…
除非征得计划投资人的同意
which is，last time I checked，your mother and I。Okay？
也就是说 你妈妈和我 明白了吗
Dad，we could sit here and
爸爸 我们可以坐这儿
just have this conversation about plans…
一直谈有关计划的问题
but for now，let's call it a night.
但是现在 还是收工吧
Let's not even clean up，right？
也别收拾屋子了 好不
Let's come back tomorrow.
明天再谈吧
Let's reboot the whole energy，
到时候我们重整旗鼓
the whole tone of this puppy…
重新看待问题
and we'll kill it，man.
我们会把它搞定的 老爸
Team Daley！Not tonight，tomorrow.
戴利传奇 今晚别谈了 等明天的
Hey，Team Daley？
嘿 戴利传奇
- Yeah？- Stop talking.
- 怎么了 - 可以闭嘴了
Okay.
好
You're gonna clean up。I'm gonna go to bed.
你在这儿收拾 我去睡觉
And then we're gonna finish this conversation tomorrow.
我们明天再谈这事儿
（自然历史博物馆）
Yeah！Get some！
耶 走你
Get some！
走你
That's it。Yeah.
就是这么任性
Hi.
嗨
I'm Larry Daley。I'm head of the Night Program.
我是拉里·戴利 夜场演出负责人
I know who you are。You're the security guard.
我知道你 你是那个保安
Yeah，also head of the Night Program.
对 也是夜场演出负责人
I'm doing some research…
我在做一些调查
and I was wondering if you could help me out.
想看看你是否能帮我一把
Mmm。Night guard doing research.
哦 夜间保安搞研究
Ooh la-la！
太阳打西边出来啦
Yeah.
我知道
Uh，I'm just looking for anything
我只是想找关于
that you might have on the Tablet of Ahkmenrah.
阿卡曼拉金碑的一切资料
Center aisle.
中心通道
- Great。- Halfway down，stacks on your left.
- 太好了 - 走到中间 左手边
Get it！
走你
So…
那么
what makes you so curious about the Tablet？
你为什么对这个金碑这么感兴趣
Oh！Just，uh…
哦 只是
Just a hobby，you know？Kind of an interest of mine.
只是个爱好 个人兴趣
I wish I could talk to these guys.
真希望我能跟他们谈谈
Well，you can't.
这是谈不了了
Yeah.
是啊
Because they're dead.
因为他们死了
Right.
对
But，uh，look at that one.
但是看那个人
Looks like a kid，huh？
像是个孩子 对吧
You didn't know him，did you？
你不会是认识他吧
C.J Fredericks.
C.J·弗雷德里克斯
He worked here.
他还在这里工作过呢
He worked here？
他在这里工作过
Yeah，when he grew up.
对啊 在他长大之后
- No。- Yeah.
- 不是吧 - 是的
He was a night guard.
他是个夜间保安
Same as you.
跟你一样
Wait a minute。C.J.
等一下 C.J
C.J Fredericks.
C.J·弗雷德里克斯
Cecil Fredericks？
就是塞西尔·弗雷德里克斯吗
Sexiest night guard we ever had.
史上最性感的夜间保安
Present company included.
包括现任
Boy，could that man move.
孩子 他那舞姿真是无人能及
Larry？
拉里
Hey，Cecil.
嗨 塞西尔
My God，it's been years！
天啊 好久不见
You look like you're doing pretty good.
你看起来过的不错
I've still got it，pal.
我还风华正茂呢 伙计
What are you doing here？
你来这儿做什么
I need to talk to you about the Tablet.
我想跟你谈谈有关金碑的事
What the heck is Short Stack doing here？
这矬子干嘛来的
Hey，Gus。You're looking well.
嗨 格斯 你气色不错
Reginald.
雷金纳德
Are you here to frame us again？
你是不是又来陷害我们的
Send us back to the slammer？
让我们去受牢狱之苦
I didn't frame you。You were actually stealing.
我可没陷害你们 你们确实偷东西了
And I was the one that got you out of jail，so…
而且还是我把你们弄出监狱的 所以
Yeah。We've got a nice life here.
我们在这儿过的非常好
The past is the past。We've moved on.
过去的事就过去了 我们都看开了
I don't think this guy's moved on.
我可不觉得这家伙看开了
Listen to him，monkey face.
好好听他说话 猴脸
We've put all that Tablet stuff behind us，Larry.
我们已经把金碑抛之脑后了 拉里
It's old news.
都是陈年往事了
Besides，we really never knew anything about that old Tablet.
而且我们对那个古老的金碑一无所知
We just worked there.
我们只是在那儿工作
Something's up with it.
它出了点事儿
I told you，I can't help you.
我跟你说了 我没法帮你
Maybe this kid can.
也许这孩子能帮我
Maybe we'd better talk alone.
我们最好私聊
Expedition like that is a pretty amazing thing…
对于一个12岁的小男孩来说
for a 12-year-old boy.
远征寻宝是一件非常美妙的事情
I tried to move on…
我曾尽力将它忘怀
but there was something about that Tablet.
但是那金碑很不一般
It's turning green，like some sort of corrosion.
它变绿了 像是被腐蚀了一样
And something's happening to Teddy and Dexter…
泰迪和德克斯特开始变得不对劲儿
Jed and Octavius.
还有杰德和奥克塔维厄斯
They're all acting weird.
他们都表现得很古怪
It's like the green rust is affecting them.
好像是绿锈会影响他们一样
「The end will come.」
末日将至
What？
什么
The locals，they warned us.
当地人警告过我们
They begged us to leave that tomb alone.
求我们不要打扰墓穴
I thought it meant the end of the world.
我当时还以为是世界末日的意思
But maybe it meant the end…
但是也许它的意思是
End of the magic？
魔法的终结
We should have listened.
我们当时真该听他们的话
Should have listened.
该听他们的话啊
Instead，we shipped Ahk and the Tablet off to New York…
我们却把阿卡和金碑运到了纽约
and his folks to England.
把他的父母送去了英格兰
Wait。Wait.
等等 等等
Ahkmenrah's parents are in England？
阿卡曼拉的父母在英格兰
It was a joint expedition.
那次是合作探险
Some of the artifacts stayed in Egypt.
有些文物留在了埃及
The rest was divided up between New York and the British Museum.
其他的被纽约和大英博物馆分摊
Ahk said that his father knew the secrets of the Tablet.
阿卡说他父亲知道金碑的秘密
I think I have to go talk to him.
我想我应该去找他谈谈
I need you to listen to me。Uh…
你听我说
Our esteemed chairwoman asked for my resignation.
我们尊贵的女主席要求我退位让贤
She said，since the Night Program was my brainchild…
她说 既然夜场演出是我的主意
that the buck starts and stops with me.
那就一人做事一人当
- I can fix it。- How？
- 我能解决问题 - 怎么解决
I need you to let me take the Tablet and Ahkmenrah to London.
你得让我把金碑和阿卡曼拉一起带到伦敦
Sorry。I'm just processing that.
抱歉 我要处理一下这个信息
Input data analysis.
输入数据分析
I've just told you I'm being fired，
我刚跟你说完 我被解雇了
and the first thing you ask…
然后你开口的第一句
is if I'd allow you to take some priceless artifacts…
却是问我能不能让你带着珍贵的文物
away with you on holiday.
跟你一起去度假
- Yes。Please。- No way.
- 是的 求你了 - 不可能
I'm asking you to please go with me on this.
我是想请你跟我站在统一战线上
- Nah。- Please.
- 额 - 求你了
Can't do it，dude.
我做不到 兄弟
Bye.
再见
- Are you gonna mug me？- What？
- 你要打劫吗 - 什么
I don't know。Just be prepared.
我不知道 就是做点心理准备
- I need you to listen to me。- Oh.
- 我要你听我说 - 哦
- Okay？- Yep.
- 好吗 - 成
- You want to know the truth？- Go on.
- 你想知道真相是吧 - 继续说
Truth is，the Tablet…
真相就是 那个金碑
The Tablet is actually magic.
那个金碑有魔力
Things really do come to life at night.
晚上那些展品真的会有生命
It's special effects.
那是特技效果
- It's not special effects。- Of course it's special effects.
- 那不是特技效果 - 当然是特技效果
How could it be special effects？
那怎么会是特技效果呢
How could it not be special effects？
那怎么就不是特技效果呢
- Because it isn't！- Of course it is！
- 因为那不是 - 因为那是
- I'm telling you，this is what happens。- What？
- 我告诉你 这是真事儿 - 什么
Sun goes down…
太阳落山之后
the Tablet starts to glow…
金碑就会开始发光
everything comes to life.
博物馆里的一切事物都有了生命
- Sure。- It's real.
- 好吧 - 这是真的
「Tablet starts to glow.」
金碑开始发光
Now I know you're mental.
我现在可知道了 你就是个精神病
Look，Leslie…
听着 莱斯利
Listen to me。I'm not gonna hurt you.
听我说 我不会伤害你的
I know。Just…
我知道 只是
What？
怎么
nobody cares about this place as much as we do，right？
没人比我们更关心这个地方了 对吧
Yeah.
对
If you don't help me…
如果你不帮我
everything that's special about it might stop…
这个地方的一切奇妙之处都将不复存在
I mean it may never come back.
而且可能永远不会复原了
I'm not asking you to understand，
我不是在强迫你理解
I'm just asking you to trust me.
只是希望你能信任我
I'd like to help you…
我愿意帮你
but I don't even work here anymore.
但这儿已经不归我管了
British Museum doesn't know that.
大英博物馆可不知道这个
The mummy and the Tablet，both.
木乃伊和金碑一起
Classic conservation job…
机密保护工作
under authority of me，of course…
是我应允的 当然
the director of this museum，which I still am.
我是博物馆的主管 而且现在仍是
Yep，okay.
成 好的
You're in.
妥了
I really could have just stayed by myself in New York.
其实我自己在纽约待着就行了
Yeah。No，that wasn't gonna happen.
呵呵 不 那不可能
- Beautiful，huh？- Yeah.
- 景色很美 是吧 - 嗯
The River Thames.
泰晤士河
Isn't this cool，man，
这不是很酷吗 孩子
you and me in London？
咱俩一起在英国
- Huh？- Yeah.
- 说话啊 - 是的
Hey，I've been thinking about that，uh，year off.
我一直在想休学那件事
Yeah？
然后呢
I think it could be cool.
我觉得挺好的
- Yeah？- Yeah.
- 真的吗 - 真的
What are you thinking？
你有什么想法吗
Yeah。Uh… Wow.
额 哇哦
I think I want to DJ in lbiza.
我想去伊比萨当DJ
In lbiza？
去伊比萨
lbiza，it's a small island off the coast of Spain.
伊比萨是西班牙海岸的一个小岛
- Do you speak Spanish？- No.
- 你会说西班牙语吗 - 不会
But that's the beautiful thing。It's about the music.
但这恰好是其美妙之处 关乎音乐
It's not inhibited by the language barrier.
是不受语言限制的
No，but you are.
是 但是你会受语言限制
Do you speak in beats？
你靠打节拍说话吗
Why are you freaking out？
你为什么这么反感
You just said this was a really cool idea.
你刚才还说这是一个很棒的想法
I'm not freaking out.
我没反感
I just want to understand what the plan is.
我只是想了解一下计划的怎么样的
You didn't go to college.
你就没上大学
Wait，now we're talking about not going to college at all？
停 现在成了压根儿不上大学了吗
- Maybe。I don't know。- Nicky.
- 也许吧 我不知道 - 尼基
Nicky。That's not…
尼基 这可不是…
Dad，you didn't go to college。You turned out fine.
爸爸 你没上大学 现在混得也不错
I turned out okay after about 20 years
我四处碰壁的奋斗了二十年
in a lot of dead ends.
才混个勉勉强强
Whatever，man.
随便吧 老爸
Don't worry about me。It's fine.
不用担心我 我挺好的
Hey，I'm always gonna worry about you.
我不可能不担心你
- I'm your dad。- Thanks.
- 我是你爸爸 - 谢谢
Sun is going down。We should get going.
太阳落山了 我们走吧
All right.
好的
Dad，what's the plan here，anyway？
爸 咱们的计划是什么
When the Tablet brings Ahkmenrah to life，
金碑把阿卡曼拉复活之后
he's gonna sneak us in.
他会偷偷把我们弄进去
- Now，get down。- What？
- 现在趴下 - 什么
Just get down！Come on，man。Part of the adventure.
趴下就行 快 冒险的一部分
Hello。Welcome to the British Museum.
你好 欢迎来到大英博物馆
My name's Tilly.
我叫蒂莉
Hi。Thank you.
你好 谢谢
I'm Larry Daley from Natural History，New York.
拉里·戴利 来自纽约自然历史博物馆
- Yeah，yeah。- I got a delivery…
- 哦 哦 - 我这儿有一份货物
for your conservation department.
是送到你们文物保护部门的
All right！
好的
So they let you travel？
这么说他们允许你出差
This is kind of unusual.
这次的情况比较特殊
Well，they let me travel。You know where？
他们也允许我出差 你猜去哪儿
- No。- Home。Here。Home.
- 不知道 - 家 这儿 家
Back here.
再回这儿来
Off to the toot-toot.
给马桶喂饭
Five-minute maximum.
最多五分钟
So that must be well wicked being a security guard in America.
在美国当保安一定很过瘾吧
- Uh… - With your gun，with a silencer，
- 额 - 佩枪 带消音器
with your ninja swords.
背着忍者刀
Right.
好吧
That's not even a little bit true.
这真是一点都不贴边儿
The only thing that I got is this.
而我只有这个
- Oh。- Hammer！It's for…
- 哦 - 锤子 这是为…
and I quote，
引用他们的原话
「Minor repairs and beautifications」
修修补补 美容美化
to the shack.
就给这小破屋子
You just hit things？
就只是敲敲打打吗
Yeah，that's catchy.
倒挺朗朗上口的
Basically worthless.
一点儿意思也没有
I can't believe we're actually still talking.
我们居然还在聊天
- It's great，though，innit？- It is.
- 多好呀 对吧 - 对
This is the most conversation I've had
真是我到这里三年来
in the three years that I've worked here.
最长的对话
I feel a connection，too.
我也有同感
Is it cool if I just make my drop？
我能进去卸货吗
- Oh，yeah。- Wonderful.
- 当然啦 - 棒
But I will have to confirm.
但我要先确认一下
Actually，that's not necessary…
其实没这个必要
because they've already confirmed it on the slip I gave you.
我刚给你的文件上边已经确认过了
Yeah，all right。Confirming.
行 确认中
- Okay。- All right.
- 好吧 - 好的
Hello。This is Dr。McPhee.
你好 我是麦克菲博士
It's the British Museum，sir.
先生 这里是大英博物馆
I'm just confirming a delivery to our conservation department.
我想确认一下艺术保护部是否要送来藏品
Yes，I signed the paperwork.
对 我签了文件
Now，if you'll excuse me，I have a museum to run.
没别的事我挂了 我还要照看博物馆呢
You，boy，get those grubby fingers off my Ming vase.
那个小孩 别用脏手碰我的明代花瓶
See？Bye.
行了吗 再见
All right.
好吧
- Good？- All right，you is legit.
- 行了吗 - 好吧 你可以进去
I is legit.
那就进吧
- Wonderful。- Confirm it.
- 很好 - 确认哒
- Thank you。- All right，I'll open the gate.
- 谢谢 - 好呢 我开门啦
Okay.
好的
Yeah，so，like，my boyfriend…
我男朋友吧…
he doesn't really like the way I do my hair.
他不喜欢我的发型
Says it looks like a golden poo sitting on my shoulder.
说看上去像一坨金色的便便团在我肩上
But I really enjoy it.
但我超喜欢
Bye，Larry！
再见 拉里
I'm not an expert…
我不是很懂
but this is feeling，just，really against the law.
但我们这样 肯定是犯法的吧
No，they have a totally different legal system here.
不 英美用的是不同的法律体系
Okay.
好吧
How we doing？
怎么样
All clear.
检查完毕
All right，let's go.
行 我们走
Larry，the others felt，perhaps，we could use some help.
拉里 其他人觉得我们可能会需要帮助
The others？
其他人
Lawrence，I couldn't sit idly by.
劳伦斯 我可不能干等着
Our very survival is at stake.
我们的生命岌岌可危
All right。Hey，Teddy。Good.
好吧 泰迪 好样的
Good man to have in a crisis.
危机中最需要的人
Attila.
匈奴王
Okay，a little muscle.
好吧 力气大
Hi，Larry.
拉里
That is a deceptively large box.
这箱子怎么可能这么大
Obviously，we came along，too！
我们也来啦
You know you'd be lost without us，Gigantor.
没我们你肯定会迷路啊 铁人
Are you serious？
你搞什么
And the monkey。All right，basically everyone.
猴子 好吧 基本上就是大家都来了
Dada！
爸爸
Oh！No，no.
我去 不是吧
No possible benefit whatsoever.
他来有毛线用啊
He really wanted to come.
他真的特别想来
Yeah，this is my son…
这是我儿子
my actual son，Nicky.
我真正的儿子 尼基
- Nicky，this is Laaa。- What's up？
- 尼基 这是拉 - 你好
He's just tracking me.
他总盯着我
Laaa.
拉
So，Lawrence…
劳伦斯
what's the plan of attack？
进攻计划是什么
We need to get to the Egyptian wing，find Ahk's father…
我们要到埃及区找到阿卡的父亲
and hopefully get the Tablet fixed.
希望他能修好金碑
All of us.
我们所有人
Laaa，that's not for eating。That's not food.
拉 那些不能吃 不是吃的
Don't…
别…
You know what？I got a job for you.
我有事要你干
Come on，come on.
来 过来
Come on.
过来
I want you to stay here and watch this door，okay？
我要你在这里看着这扇门 好吗
Make sure nobody comes in or out。Okay？
确保没人进出 行吗
Good。You're gonna be a guard，just like me.
好 你可以当个保安 像我一样
All right.
好的
No。Come here.
不 过来
Stay here…
待在这里
and put your hands on the door.
把手放门上
- Good，stay。- Stay！
- 好 留下 - 留下
Good。That's right。You stay here.
很好 对了 你待在这里
Stay here.
待在这里
Stay。Right.
留下 对
No。Stay.
不 留下
- Stay！- Stay.
- 留下 - 留下
Look there。Good。Stay.
看前面 对 留下
No。Good。Stay.
不 对 留下
No。Stay.
不 留下
Stay！
留下
Don't… Don't move.
不 不许动
Don't move.
不许动
No。Good。Okay.
不许 对了
Okay，listen up，guys.
好 听着 伙计们
This place is waking up for the first time…
这地方是第一次醒过来
and we have no idea what's out there，
我们不知道会发生什么
so stay together，all right？
所以我们不能走散 知道吗
I know it's spooky，big guy.
我知道挺恐怖的 大块头
Just stay close.
跟紧点儿
What kind of haunted hootenanny is this，boys？
这都是些什么玩意儿啊
We're all finding this super creepy，right？
不是只有我觉得很诡异 对吧
They're just a little freaked out.
他们只是吓坏了
First time we came alive it took some getting used to.
我们第一次醒过来也用了很久才适应
Hey，there。Just heading to Egypt.
你好 我们要去埃及
Come on。This way.
来吧 这边
Hear that？
听到了吗
Hear what？
听到什么
That.
这个
We'll just be down here if anyone needs us.
我们在这里面哦 有需要就叫我们
We're not scared。It's just more comfortable.
不是我们害怕 是这里边舒服
Lawrence…
劳伦斯
I think it's safe to say that we're in a bit of trouble.
我觉得我们有点儿小麻烦
I know how to handle this guy.
我知道怎么搞定这家伙
You mind？
介意借给我吗
Thanks.
谢谢
Dad。What are you doing？
爸 你要做什么
How do you think I tamed your pal Rexy？
你以为我是怎么驯服你哥们儿雷克斯的
Hi，there.
你好啊
I bet you're not so mean，are you？Huh？
你不是坏孩子 对吧
I bet you're not so mean.
我说你肯定很乖
No，you're just a little puppy，right？
你是只乖狗狗 对吧
You're just a little puppy who wants to play.
你是想玩游戏的乖狗狗
You want to play，huh？
想玩吗
Want to play fetch？
想玩接骨头游戏吗
Yeah？
想吗
You want to play with this bone？
想和这根骨头玩玩吗
Ah！Yeah！
好嘞
Here you go。Go fetch.
来吧 去叼回来
Go fetch！
接住
- Lawrence？- Yeah？
- 劳伦斯 - 怎么
- May I suggest a different plan？- What？
- 我能提个建议吗 - 什么建议
Run！
逃跑
Close it，close it！
快关门 关门
Okay。I think we're…
好了 我想我们…
Get back！Everybody，get back！
退后 大家全都退后
All right。You don't want to fetch？
好 你既然不吃敬酒
- Fetch on this。- What？
- 那就吃罚酒吧 - 什么
- Oh，that's close！- Need some help？
- 好险啊 - 需要帮助吗
- What？- Move.
- 啥 - 让开
Attila，you okay？
匈奴王 你还好吗
- You might want to… - No.
- 你可能要… - 不
Here…
来
hold this.
拿着
OK。That was actually very cool.
好吧 真是非常酷
Sir Lancelot，at your service.
兰斯洛特爵士 乐意为您效劳
Thank you。That was amazing.
谢谢 太酷炫了
Theodore Roosevelt…
西奥多·罗斯福
President of the United States of America.
美利坚合众国总统
I have no idea what that means.
我根本不知道那是个啥
I'm Larry，and this is my son，Nick.
我是拉里 这是我儿子尼克
You have a noble face，Nick.
你有一张贵族的脸 尼克
- Thanks。- Thanks for the help.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢你帮忙
Now，you…
你吧
You remind me of a man I once knew at Camelot.
你很像我在卡米洛特认识的一个人
Really？
真的吗
One of the Knights of the Round Table？
圆桌骑士之一吗
No，Erik.
不 埃里克
Erik？
埃里克
Our fool.
我们的小丑
He was the funniest fool I ever met.
是我见过的最好玩的小丑
He was so good，he didn't even have to do anything.
简直太棒 他都不用特意搞笑
He could just walk into a room and you'd laugh.
只需要走进来 你就能笑翻
Hmm.
是嘛
- You have what he had。The gift。- That's weird.
- 你和他一样 那种天赋 - 真神奇
- You could be a fool。- I don't know about that.
- 你也可以当小丑 - 这可不一定
Oh，come on，of course you could！
你可以的啦
We'd get you one of those
我们先给你弄个帽子
hats with the funny little dangly bells.
边上吊着很多小铃铛的那种
Dangly bells？
小铃铛
「Dangly bells.」
「小铃铛」
Didn't I tell you？The gift.
我说得没错吧 天赋
He does what seems like nothing.
他一点儿都不刻意
A sort of deadpan…
就这么一张木头脸
tiny little…
就一点点点…
Expressionless，you know，sort of a…
没什么特别表情 就那么…
sort of thing.
那种感觉
Just like Erik.
和埃里克一模一样
Sounds like a great guy。We got to get going，so…
听起来他人不错啊 我们得走了
Ah，Camelot.
卡米洛特啊
Okay.
好吧
Someday，I shall return to its mighty towers…
总有一天我会回到那雄伟的城堡里
to King Arthur…
回到亚瑟王
and Queen Guinevere.
和格温娜维尔王后身边
Sweet…
迷人的
beauteous Guinevere.
美丽的格温娜维尔
But I'm sworn not to until I have completed my quest.
但我发誓完成使命之前绝不回去
I must find the Holy Grail.
我必须找到圣杯
Well，good luck with that.
祝你好运
And thanks for the help again.
再次感谢你帮忙
We got to get to Egypt，so we'll see you.
我们得去埃及了 回见
- I will lead you。- No，it's okay.
- 我带你们去 - 不用了
Halt，Dangly Bells！
停下 小铃铛
There is strange magic in the air，
这里有奇怪的魔法
and dangerous beasts are afoot.
还有危险的野兽在活动
It is the duty of a true knight…
一名真正的骑士
to protect and care for those in need.
必须保护照顾那些有难的人们
We're off.
我们走吧
I guess he's coming with us.
看来是甩不掉他了
Larry！
拉里
Jed and Octavius？
杰德和奥克塔维厄斯
They must have fallen out while we were running.
我们跑的时候他们可能掉出来了
Jed？
杰德
Octavius！
奥克塔维厄斯
Jedediah！
杰迪戴亚
Jed！Octo！
杰德 奥克塔
Oh，no.
不
Is that Octavius's cape？
是奥克塔维厄斯的披风吗
Here.
拿着
- Nicky。- Yeah.
- 尼基搭把手 - 好
Guys？
伙计们
Gigantor！
铁人
Jed？
杰德
They won't last long in those heating vents，Lawrence.
劳伦斯 在加热通风管里他们撑不久的
At their size，they'll
就他们那小身板
bake like tiny little scarabs in the Sinai.
肯定会被烤得像西奈的甲虫似的
Too dark？
说的太黑暗了点吗
This is the end，boy！
就到这了 兄弟
This is the last roundup！
这是最后的决斗
Hold my hand！
牵住我的手
Why？
为毛
Never mind.
当我没说
（西翼）
We're a long way from home，boy.
想回去恐怕不容易了
Did you ask me to hold your hand？
你刚是不是让我牵你手了
No.
没有
Mmm-hmm.
好的吧
Jedo！
杰德
Octo！
奥克塔
They could be anywhere between here and the intake vent.
他们可能在从这儿到进气口的任何地方
What do you see，Dex？
小德 你看到什么了
You know he's a monkey，Lawrence.
劳伦斯 他是只猴子
He can't talk.
他不能说话
No，but he can fit.
是啊 但他能钻进去
Nicky… give me your phone.
尼基 手机给我
- Why？- For Dex.
- 干嘛 - 给小德
I don't understand one thing that's going on here.
到底怎么了我完全一头雾水
Yeah。I don't，either。Dad，what's going on？
我也是 老爸 怎么回事
I'm sort of set up to track your phone.
我好像是追踪了你的手机
You're sort of set up to track my phone？You track my phone？
好像追踪了 你居然追踪我的手机
Yeah，I'm your dad。I'm looking out for you.
是啊 我是你爹 我是为了保护你
No。No。Hold up.
不是 你等等
「Spying on」 is not the same thing
监视某人和保护某人
as just looking out for someone.
完全是两码事
You'll get it back，I promise.
会还给你的 我保证
But right now，it's going on the monkey's back.
但现在 要先放猴子背上
All right。Dex，come here.
好了 小德 过来
Thanks，man.
谢了
Listen。I need you to go down there and find them，all right？
听着 我要你下去找到他们 好吗
Think you can handle it？
你觉得能行吗
Good man.
好孩子
Stay safe.
注意安全
I think it's right here.
应该就是这里
「Right here.」
就是这里
Classic.
真经典
Ah，the gift of laughter.
搞笑的天赋啊
Thank you，Dangly Bells.
谢谢你啊 小铃铛
First quest？
第一个使命吗
Uh，not exactly.
也不是
I thought you were going to Egypt.
你们不是要去埃及吗
We are，but we got to do this first.
是啊 但得先救他们
That's not how a quest works.
使命可不能这样对待
A quest is one thing。It's not，like，「Holy Grail and a monkey.」
使命只有一个 不能既是圣杯又是猴子
Yeah，well，my guys are missing
是啊 可是我的人不见了
and Dexter's gonna find them.
而德克斯特能找到他们
What is the quest？Gold？
那你们的使命是什么 黄金
Fountain of Youth？
不老泉
Magic Tablet.
魔法金碑
It's that thing Ahk is holding.
就是阿卡拿的那东西
It shouldn't be too hard to take it from him.
要从他那里抢过来也不是太难啊
He seems well-toned and lean…
他很瘦 线条是不错
but weak.
但很羸弱
It would be like taking candy from a feeble Egyptian baby.
就跟从埃及小宝宝手上抢糖一样容易
No，we're not trying to take it。We're trying to fix it.
我们没有要抢 我们要修它
There's something wrong with it.
它出了点问题
It's kind of complicated.
说来话长
It might be less complicated
如果你别再继续努力找小猩猩
if you stopped following a chimpanzee.
也许情况也就不那么长了
He's not a chimpanzee。He's a capuchin.
它不是猩猩 它是僧帽猴
The fool seems agitated.
弄臣似乎很焦虑
That's often his way.
他常常会那样
But I assure you，he's no fool.
但我保证 他绝对不傻
Is it true what he says？
他说的是真的吗
The Tablet that you carry is magic？
你拿的那块金碑有魔力
It is，indeed.
确实如此
Everything around you has
你周遭的一切
come to life tonight for the very first time…
在今夜首次苏醒
all because of this Tablet.
都是因为这块金碑
Amazing.
了不起
Then they're not real？
所以他们不是真的
They're as real as any of us.
他们与我们一样真实
Yes，but we're real people.
没错 但我们是真人
They're just things.
他们只是东西
And they don't even know.
而他们并未发觉
They must be unbelievably stupid.
他们一定十分愚蠢
It can be confusing at first.
最初是会有点困惑
Hello，frog！
你好呀 青蛙
Keep hopping！
继续跳吧
You're real！
你是真的
Guys，I think we're gonna have to cut through Asia.
大伙们 我们要穿过亚洲馆
Not a clue.
他完全没发觉
None.
没错
I can't really see much.
我什么也看不清
We could jump down，hope for the best.
我们可以跳下去 祈求上天保佑
But we have no idea what's down there.
但我们不知道下面有什么
We don't know what's up here，either.
我们也不知道这里有什么
This is a Roman city.
一座罗马古城
I can feel the familiar pull of history in its very foundations.
这里散发的历史感如此似曾相识
Where the heck is everybody？
人都去哪里了
I've seen this town before，I'm sure of it.
我以前见过这座城 我很肯定
Romans？
罗马人
I see you have the name of a lady on your arm.
我看到你手臂上写了一位女士的名字
Andrea。Yeah.
安德莉亚 对
So this Lady Andrea is your Guinevere.
这位安德莉亚女士便是你的格温娜维尔
Does any man stand between you and your ladylove？
有人阻止你们相爱吗
Yeah，actually。My dad kind of messed things up the other night.
其实我爸那天有点把事情搞砸了
- Nick。- Oh，we're stopping.
- 尼克 - 我们不走了吗
Let no man stand between you and your destiny.
不能让任何人阻碍你的命运
Oh，「Destiny」 may be overstating it a bit.
说是「命运」太夸张了
We just have calculus together.
我们不过一起上微积分课
It's more one of those…
其实更像那种
fleeting moments of eye contact.
稍纵即逝的眼神接触
「Who's gonna look away first？」
「谁先转移视线」
But I get you，yeah，「No man…
但我听懂了 任何人也不能
Good。Okay.
很好
「Liepwop.」
贝庞
Liepwop.
Doesn't ring a bell.
没见过啊
Now who's this son of a gun？
这个王八蛋是谁
- Pompeii！- I'm sorry.
- 庞培 - 不好意思
- I'm having trouble hearing you！- Pompeii！
- 我听不太清你说什么 - 庞培
No comprendo，amigo…
哥们儿 我听不懂你的话
because you got the thing in front of you！
因为有东西挡住你了
What are they doing？
他们在干什么
Where in the blazes are they stampeding off to？
他们慌张地逃去哪里
Was it something we said？
是因为我们说的话吗
Come on back to liepwop！
快回贝庞来
There's plenty of room！Come on back！
这里好宽敞 快回来
They're as crazy as road lizards.
他们跟蜥蜴一样疯狂
People are strange.
这些人太奇怪了
Hey，guy，We're just passing through.
你好 朋友 我们只是路过
It's a Garuda from Tibet.
这是西藏的金翅鸟
A Garuda？
金翅鸟
Hi，Garuda。How you doing？
你好 金翅鸟 你好吗
Garuda！How you doing？
金翅鸟 你好吗
Cool，great.
很好
Okay。We just…
好吧 我们只是
You know what？We just got to get through。I don't have time.
我们必须要过去 没时间了
Please。Okay.
拜托 好吧
I'm not gonna play this game with you.
我不会跟你玩这个游戏的
I got to go through。Really.
我真的要过去
Get back.
退后
- A dragon。- No，it's not a dragon。It's a…
- 龙 - 不 不是龙 这是
（相柳 象征灾难之蛇妖）
It's a Xiangliu.
这是相柳
Mythical snake demon.
传说中的蛇妖
It looks like a dragon。I say we kill it.
看着还是像龙 我说杀了它
What？No，it's asleep.
什么 不 它在睡觉
You're right.
你说得对
It's not very sporting to kill it while it's asleep.
趁它睡觉时偷袭不够刺激
Let's wake it up and then kill it.
我们叫醒它然后再杀了它
I shall go first，and I shall take the boy.
我先上 孩子跟我走
What are you…？No！You're not gonna take the boy.
什么 不 孩子不能跟你走
- Why not？- Because he's a boy！
- 为什么 - 因为他还是个孩子
Larry，there comes a time in every man's life…
拉里 每个人生命中
when he must slay his own dragon.
都必须经历屠龙的那刻
Not this kid，all right？
这个孩子不行
He still hasn't finished
他还没写完
all his thank-you notes from his bar mitzvah.
犹太成人礼里的感谢卡
Anyway，that's just an expression.
那只是个比喻
Not where I come from.
我的故乡不是这样的
He's not gonna slay his dragon right now.
他现在不会去屠龙
We're gonna go around it.
我们绕过它
We're gonna go around now，or else we're gonna lose the signal.
现在就绕 不然要失去信号了
Come on.
来吧
liepwop.
贝庞
Pompeii！
庞培
liepwop。Are you sure you're reading that right，pal？
贝庞 你确定念的是对的吗 朋友
Pompeii！
庞培
（庞培）
「Pompeii.」
「庞培」
「Ask not what your country can do for you…
「不要问你的国家能为你做什么」
「Ask what you can do for your country.」
「问问你能为你的国家做什么」
There it goes again！
又来了
Attila！Shh！
匈奴王 嘘
- Teddy！- Charge！
- 泰迪 - 冲啊
Fantastic！
太棒了
It's awake！
它醒了
Now we can kill it！
现在我们可以杀它了
Dad！
爸
Nicky！
尼基
I'll get the boy！
我去救那个男孩
- Ever used a blade？- Only in World of Warcraft！
- 以前玩过剑吗 - 在魔兽世界里玩过
You're about to learn.
你看着学吧
「The only thing we have to fear is fear itself！」
「我们唯一的恐惧就是恐惧本身」
「Doing a heck of a job，Brownie.」
「布朗 干得不错」
（点击器）
Behind you！
你后面
Duck！
闪开
Last roundup，kemosabe！
最后的战役 好基友
Time to slap on the barbecue sauce，boy！
是时候乱涂烧烤酱了
Huh？What？
什么
No，no！You wouldn't！
不 不 你不能这样
He must！
他别无选择
Clear！
安全
We must never speak of what happened here today.
我们对今天发生的一切绝口不提
Come on！That wasn't necessary！
拜托 有这必要吗
It's out！
火都灭了呀
These things really do save lives.
原来这些东西确实能救命
Are you all right？
你没事吧
Are you all right，my dear？
你没事吧 亲爱的
- You okay？- Yeah，thanks.
- 你还好吗 - 没事 谢谢
You fought bravely，sire.
你刚才很勇敢 阁下
One day，I promise you，
我保证 总有一天
we shall drink dragon's blood from the victor's cup.
我们会在胜利的酒杯中饮龙血
I'm good with just，like，soda or water，too.
我喝苏打水或水就可以了
But I like the energy we got going.
但我很喜欢刚才的活动
From now on，you must choose your own path.
从现在起 你必须选择自己的道路
And let no man tell you otherwise.
不要被别人左右
We better let Larry know we're okay.
应该让拉里知道我们没事
Turn around.
转身
Larry's probably worried about us.
拉里肯定在担心我们
How are we going to find them now？
现在我们要怎么找他们
Lawrence？
劳伦斯
I fear we've turned a corner.
情况恐怕恶化了
I'm becoming wax again，son.
孩子 我正在慢慢变回蜡像
All right。We'll look for them later.
好吧 等一下再找他们
We got to get to Egypt now.
我们得马上去埃及
Wait，shouldn't we keep looking for Jed and Octavius？
等等 不找杰德和奥克塔维厄斯了吗
Nick is right.
尼克说得对
A true knight never shirks his duties.
真正的骑士绝不逃避责任
If we don't get to Egypt soon we're not gonna save anybody.
如果再不去埃及 我们谁也救不了
Dada say，「Stay！」
爸比说 「留下」
Stay！
留下
Dada say Laaa no eat.
爸比说拉不吃
Stay，Laaa！
留下 拉
（埃及馆 法老王年代）
This is it.
到了
Perhaps I should accompany you in.
也许我应该陪你进去
No，I think we got it from here.
不 我想我们应该就此分别
- Really？- Yeah。No，we're good.
- 真的吗 - 是 我们搞得定
Right。Well…
好吧
friends…
朋友们
Larry…
拉里
clown-faced keeper of the magic Tablet…
魔法金碑的小丑脸守护者
I shall never forget your bravery.
我永远不会忘记你的勇敢
Nor your jests.
以及你的滑稽
Bye.
再见
I shall not say goodbye.
我不应该说再见
- I am。- What？
- 我在说再见 - 什么
I'm gonna say goodbye。I have to go，I'm sorry.
我要说再见 我要走了 对不起
I'll see you.
再见
Really，man，thank you.
真的谢谢你
For everything.
谢谢这一切
I haven't seen these walls for many a moon.
我已有许多夜没见过这些墙壁了
Ahkmen？
阿卡曼
Mother.
母亲
Father.
父亲
Welcome home，my son.
欢迎回家 儿子
I want you to meet my friends.
我想给你介绍一下我的朋友们
I am Merenkahre…
我是门罗卡拉
Pharaoh of the Nile and Father to the Son of the Sun.
尼罗河的法老 太阳之子的父亲
And I am Shepseheret…
我是茜茜赫特
the Glittering Jewel of the Nine Kingdoms.
九国熠熠发光的珠宝
And I am Larry.
我是拉里
Guardian of Brooklyn.
布鲁克林守护者
Yes.
是的
I actually live in Manhattan now.
我现在实际上住在曼哈顿
I know，but it doesn't sound as cool.
我知道 但它听起来没那么酷
We would be very honored
如果您能检查一下金碑
if you could take a look at the Tablet.
我们会感到很荣幸
There's something happening with it.
它有些不对劲
We don't understand what it is.
我们不懂为什么
You are speaking with a pharaoh.
你在和法老说话
Kiss my staff.
亲吻我的权杖
Is it okay if I don't？
我不亲可以吗
You will show respect.
你必须表现尊敬
I am the descendant of Ra，the sun god.
我乃太阳神之后代
I understand that and I totally respect you.
我非常理解 也非常尊敬您
I just don't pray to Ra，so…
我并不信仰太阳神 因此
The Egyptian gods are the only true gods.
埃及神是唯一的真神
Well，we try to stay a little more open-minded.
我们不想太狭隘
I mean，Sacajawea，she honors her spiritual ancestors…
比如萨卡加维亚 她信奉祖先的灵魂
and you pray to some sort of goat god，Attila？
你崇拜的是山羊神吧 匈奴王
I'm half-lrish，half-Jewish…
我是半爱尔兰裔半犹太裔
You are？I love Jews！
是吗 我爱犹太人
We owned 40，000 of them！
我们拥有4万多个犹太人
- Such lovely people。- Here we go.
- 他们太可爱了 - 又来了
They were very happy，always singing with the candles.
他们很开心 总拿着蜡烛歌唱
Yeah。They really weren't happy.
其实他们真的不开心
- Really？- No。They left.
- 真的吗 - 是的 他们离开了
They spent about 40 years in the desert trying to escape.
为了逃亡他们在沙漠中度过了四十年
Yeah。We have dinner once a year and talk about it.
我们每年一次的晚餐上都会说这件事
It's a big deal for us.
这对我们来说很重要
Listen，could you take a look at that Tablet？
您能看看金碑吗
There's something wrong with it.
它出了点问题
It's losing its power.
它的力量在流失
Do you think you could fix it？
您能修好它吗
To do that，I would have to divulge the secret of the Tablet.
那样的话我就必须说出金碑的秘密
I promise we won't tell anybody.
我保证不告诉别人
No.
不行
I'll kiss your staff.
我会亲吻您的权杖
Too late.
晚了
Father，why do you insist on keeping this to yourself？
父亲 为什么你就是不肯说呢
The secret was to be passed down to you at the proper time.
秘密必须在合适的时候才能传给你
Well，it has been 4，000 years.
已经都四千年了
Now seems like a good time.
我看不如就现在吧
You were born at midnight.
你是在午夜降生的
I was Pharaoh…
我那时是法老
and I had seen wonders most men only dream of.
我阅过无数人类梦寐以求的瑰宝
But when I first gazed upon you…
但当我第一次见到你
you were instantly more precious to me…
我便知道对我来说你比任何
than all the wonders of the ancient world.
古代世界的瑰宝更珍贵
I knew I could never bear to say goodbye.
我知道我无法忍受与你分别
I commanded the High Priest to create a gift to you，my son…
我命令大祭司为你打造一份礼物 儿子
using all we had learned of the mysteries of the afterlife.
用尽我们对死后世界的一切知识
Forged in the temple of Khonsu，god of the moon…
在孔苏 月神也是夜行人守护神的
and watcher over nighttime travelers…
神殿里 我们锻造了
the Tablet of Ahkmenrah.
阿卡曼拉金碑
Our tomb was designed to
陵墓的设计
channel Khonsu's rays down to the Tablet…
使月神之光照耀金碑
rejuvenating its powers every night.
夜夜复原其力量
The moon god bestowed his power upon the Tablet…
月亮神将其力量赠予金碑
so that，as long as it bathed in his light…
只要其沐浴在月光下
our family could be together forever，
我们一家即可永远在一起
and not even death could part us.
死亡也无法将我们分离
It's been away from Khonsu's light too long.
如今它已远离月神之光太久
My son！
儿子
What is happening to you？
你怎么了
It needs moonlight…
它需要月光
otherwise we shall all be dead by sunrise.
否则天亮时我们都会死去
Hurry！
快
If the Tablet dies…
如果金碑逝去
nothing can bring it back！
没有任何事物能重赋它力量
（埃及艳后）
What are you doing？
你干什么
The Tablet。Now.
金碑给我 快
Wait，listen to me。That thing is dying.
等等 听我说 那东西快死了
If it doesn't get moonlight…
如果它不吸取月光
everything ends，like，for real.
一切都将结束 永远的结束
King Arthur wasted years searching for the Holy Grail.
亚瑟王浪费许多年月寻找圣杯
To think it was a Tablet all along.
原来它一直是块金碑
Would you just give it to me？You don't know what you're doing！
把它给我 你根本不知道自己在做什么
My quest is complete.
我的使命完成了
I ride for Camelot tonight.
今夜我将奔赴卡米洛特
Just keep it，okay？
那你就留着 行吗
But just put it in the moonlight
但要把它放在月光底下
and turn that center piece.
还要把中间那块转过来
Sorry，not my first quest.
抱歉 那不是我的首要使命
And by the way，Erik was much funnier than you！
还有 埃里克比你搞笑多了
Go get the others.
叫上大伙
We can't let him leave the building！
不能让他离开这里
Whoa！Easy there，partner！Slow it down！
镇定 伙计 给我慢点
I don't know who you are…
我不知道你是谁
but I'm pretty dang sure that Tablet don't belong to you.
但我相当确定那个金碑不属于你
Now wait a second！
等等
Come back here！This ain't over！
给我回来 这事没完
You'll rue the day you mocked us with your huge sword
你会为今天用巨剑和醉人的蓝眼睛
and hypnotic blue eyes！
嘲笑我们的行为后悔的
His eyes are very blue.
他眼睛是很蓝啊
Speak softly and carry a big stick.
（艾舍尔作品）
温言在口 大棒在手
Lawrence，we have a problem.
劳伦斯 我们有麻烦了
This one turned to wax as well.
这只手也变回蜡像了
I have a saying，too.
我也有句名言
「Speak loudly and carry a bigger stick.」
「恶言在口 只需更粗的大棒在手」
- It's over there！- You mean up there.
- 在那边 - 是在上面
Come on.
来吧
Got it.
拿到了
- Teddy。- The Tablet，now！
- 泰迪 - 金碑 给我
I shan't ask you again，fool！
我不会再问第二遍 你个弄臣
And this is giving me a headache！
绕得我头都晕了
Give me the Tablet！
金碑给我
Let me go，Lawrence.
放手吧 劳伦斯
No！Teddy，no！
不 泰迪 不要
Teddy！
泰迪
There.
这不就得了
That'll be mine.
归我了
Hey，that was a good one.
刚那招不错
No idea that would work.
没想到能成功
Larry！
拉里
Hey，you guys，how you doing？
伙计们 你们没事吧
Still in one piece that can ensure！
胳膊腿还在
Octavius，I think this belongs to you.
奥克塔维厄斯 我想这是你的
Thank you.
谢谢
I don't understand.
我不明白
Why is Lancelot staying strong while we get weaker？
怎么兰斯洛特还能跑能跳我们却逐渐衰弱
It's his first night.
这是他苏醒的第一晚
Newborns are stronger but it matters not.
新生儿更强壮 但也没有用
Unless we succeed，he，too，will be dead come the dawn.
除非我们成功 不然太阳出来他也会死
We can't let him leave the building.
不能让他离开博物馆
Sir，can you go back to Egypt，in case he comes through there？
先生 请你回埃及以防他从那里跑了
- Of course。- Nicky，take Attila，check the loading dock.
- 当然 - 尼基和匈奴王看着装货口
- Got it。- Teddy，go to the South Wing，cover the side doors.
- 收到 - 泰迪去南翼 看好侧门
I got the main entrance.
我负责主入口
You！I knew you smelled a bit off！
你 我就知道你有点不对劲
Didn't you just see that？
你看到刚过去的了吗
See what？
看到什么
The knight on the horse that just rode through！
一个中世纪骑士骑着马过去了
Stop trying to distract me with your magical fantasy！
别用你的幻想害我分心
I found your filthy twin，here，in the freight room！
我在货仓找到你这个脏兮兮的孪生兄弟了
He's not my twin.
他不是我兄弟
I got him，and what could he say for himself？
我抓到他了 他有什么好给自己辩解的
Shut up！Shut up in your face！
闭嘴 你丫闭嘴
Shut up right now！Do you want to be smashed？
给我闭嘴 你想被锤吗
Yeah，you can run，but if you leave those gates…
你跑啊 但你要是跑出围栏
I swear to you，your hideous doppelganger…
我发誓 你这个丑了吧唧的
who looks a lot like the lead singer of the Counting Crows…
看着像「数乌鸦合唱团」主唱的二重身
will get it！
就会挨我一锤
Dada.
爸比
That's right.
没错
It compute with him.
他小命就在我锤下
Dada.
爸比
Damn it！
该死
Laaa.
拉
If you see me do something dumb，don't imitate me，okay？
看到我做蠢事的时候别学我 好吗
It's basically what I keep telling Nick.
其实我也一直在跟尼克这么说
He just doesn't get it，you know？
但他就是不明白 懂吗
I mean，he's a smart kid…
他很聪明
but I just want to give him the tools that I didn't have.
但我想给他我不曾有过的机会
I mean，get the degree，then take a break.
先上好学 再去休假
Get the degree，then take a break.
Laaa！Laaa，stop that！
拉 拉 住手
Stop it！
停下
Okay.
好了
What？Excuse me！Hey！
什么 你们干什么
Hi。Hey。Sorry.
你好 很抱歉
I'm Nick，this is Dexter，Attila the Hun.
我叫尼克 这是德克斯特 匈奴王汗
Oh，yes，so lovely to meet you.
见到你们真高兴
Now meet this hammer！
现在见识见识锤子
Don't do that.
别这样
I'm super sorry。I know it's a
抱歉 我知道信息量很大
lot going on，Hun，monkey.
又是匈奴王又是猴子
Wow，what？So much weird。Huge amount to process.
什么鬼 好奇怪 需要消化
Right？Okay，sorry.
是吧 对不起了
- Thank you。- You won't get away with this！
- 谢谢你 - 你跑不掉的
I'm making sketches of you in my mind right now！
我现在大脑已经在画你们的肖像了
Boy with freckles，
雀斑男
fat Asian with hair extensions，evil monkey.
有接发的胖亚洲人 坏猴子
I guess it's just parenting，you know？
我想应该是家教问题吧
And he comes from a divorced family…
他出身离异家庭
so I'm sure he has a lot of conflicted feelings about me…
所以他心里对我应该也是五味杂陈
and there might be some Oedipal stuff at play in there，or…
可能有点恋母情结
I get it.
我懂
I wasn't there a lot of the time.
我确实没有经常陪他
So I think I might be projecting my own guilt…
所以我应该是映射了我自己的愧疚
and taking it out on him in ways…
然后在不知不觉中
that I'm not even aware of.
反映到了对待他的方式上
What？
什么
Door.
门
Head.
头
Okay，I…
好吧 我
Open…
开
head.
头
Open your mind！
打开思路
Yes！Yeah，well，you're right.
对 没错 你说得对
That's the challenge.
但问题又来了
I mean，it's all contextual，and I do.
这都有前后联系 我也知道
I keep looking at him
我教育他的方式
through the lens of how my parents raised me…
都是仿照我父母对我的教育方式
when，in reality，he's his own person.
但是事实上 他是一个独立个案
And，yeah，we share the same DNA…
没错 我们是有部分相同的基因
but honestly，he's much more evolved than I ever was.
但说实话 他比我成熟得多了
I don't want to let my own ego and childhood history…
我不想让我的自负心和童年阴影
stop him from making the mistakes he needs to make…
阻止他吃一堑长一智
to become the person that he's meant to be.
然后成长为他理应成为的大人
Open the door with your head.
是用头撞开门
Yes！
好的
Good，Laaa。Let's go！Ah！
好样的 拉 走了
- Everybody okay？- Yes，Lawrence.
- 大家都没事吧 - 是的 劳伦斯
Attila and your boy secured the lady guard in her booth.
匈奴王和你儿子把女保安关在门房里了
I don't know how long it will hold her，though.
但不太清楚能关她多久
We gotta find Lancelot…
我们要找到兰斯洛特
but somebody has to make sure she doesn't get out.
但得有人确保她不会逃出来
Yeah。Laaa，okay.
是的 拉 好的
You know what you have to do？
你知道该怎么做吧
Stay！
留下
That's right。Just make sure she stays in there.
没错 确保她一直待在里面
- Stay！- Good！Go！
- 留下 - 好样的 去吧
Dada say，「Stay」！
爸比说「留下」
Lawrence！
劳伦斯
I can't move my arms.
我胳膊动不了了
We're becoming less useful by the minute.
我们越来越虚弱了
Come on，big guy.
来吧 大块头
What？You okay there？Huh？
什么 你还好吧
Something's up with your eye，but…
你眼睛好像有点不对劲
I don't know。It's just kind of going…
我不知道 就是有点那什么
You gotta relax，okay？
你得放松 好吗
Calm down！
冷静下来
Attila！Attila！
匈奴王 匈奴王
Attila doesn't hyperventilate.
匈奴王不会吓得喘不过气
You pillage！
你强取
You plunder！
你豪夺
You don't freak out.
你不会崩溃
Okay？
好吗
Dad，there's，like，8 million people in this city.
爸爸 城里面有八百万人
He could be literally anywhere by now.
他现在真的在哪都有可能
We'll find him.
我们会找到他的
We have to.
必须得找到
I'm coming，my love.
吾爱 我来了
Blimey！
我的天
He came this way…
他从这边走
traveling 4 leagues per hour.
四里格每小时的速度
No！
别
Never run from a big cat，Lawrence.
遇到狮子不能跑 劳伦斯
Gigantor，get your flashlight out！
铁人 快把手电筒拿出来
These cats want to play！
这些猫咪想玩
Whoo-wee！He's got it，boy！
好样的 他拿到了
Well played，sir.
干得好 先生
Run！
跑呀
Where the devil could Lancelot be？
兰斯洛特到底在哪
Come on！
这边
You better let me out of here，you revolting ape-man！
你最好放我出来 你这恶心的猿人
What are you staring at？Stop looking at me！
你看什么看 别看了
Have you never seen a beautiful，
没见过我这么漂亮
attractive，gorgeous woman before…
迷人 魅力四射
who could be a model if she didn't love pizza so much？
要是不爱吃匹萨都能去当模特的美女啊
I know what you're playing at…
我知道你想干什么
and it ain't working.
告诉你 没用的
Not working.
没用的
Wait，it is kind of working.
好吧 好像有点用
What have they done to Camelot？
他们对卡米洛特都干了些什么
In short，there's simply not
简而言之 没有什么地方
a more congenial spot
能比卡米洛特
for happily ever-aftering
更适合永远
than here in…
幸福快乐地
Camelot
生活下去
At long last！
久违了
- Guinevere，my love。- Hi.
- 格温娜维尔 吾爱 - 你好
Can I help you，mate？
有什么能帮你的吗
It is I…
是我啊
Sir Lancelot.
我是兰斯洛特爵士啊
I have fulfilled my quest.
我完成我的使命了
Sorry。I'm sorry.
抱歉 不好意思
I'm not actually Guinevere.
我不是真的格温娜维尔
I'm Alice Eve，and I think you got a bit confused.
我是爱丽丝·伊芙 你可能搞混了
Maybe you saw me on stage…
你可能看过我的演出
Your voice is like music…
你的声音如此悦耳动听
but I have no idea what you're saying.
但我完全不知道你在说什么
Okay。Hey.
好了 听着
Hey，man.
听着 伙计
Hey，buddy。Um…
缓过神来 老兄
What she's saying is she's not Guinevere because she's an actor.
她是说 她是扮演格温娜维尔的演员
Okay？So am l.
好吗 我也是演员
An actor？
什么演员
Yeah。Yeah.
是的
You know？
你知道的
Do the crown.
王冠摘下来
Oh，sorry，of course。Hugh Jackman.
抱歉 休·杰克曼
It was the crown.
戴上王冠认不出来了
I know，the whole…
是吧 这一套看着不太像
Huge Ackman？
大演员
Uh… That's a ridiculous name！
什么破名字
It doesn't even sound real！
听着就像扯淡
Only a coward would conceal his true identity，Arthur.
只有懦夫才会用假名 亚瑟
No，it's Hugh Jackman.
不 是休·杰克曼
I，on the other hand…
而另一方面
carry the treasure you sought…
我带来了你寻求已久
but could never find.
却无处可觅的宝藏
Behold the key to life everlasting！
看啊 永生之门的钥匙
Okay，I love the costume…
我挺喜欢你的戏服
I love the enthusiasm…
也喜欢这份对演艺事业的热情
but you're gonna have to get off stage now.
但你真心得下台了
Sir Lancelot，ladies and gentlemen。Sir Lancelot.
兰斯洛特爵士 女士们先生们
Yes！
是的
Very good.
真不错
Shame on you，Arthur！
真丢人 亚瑟
You don't deserve your crown，
你配不上你的王冠
and you don't deserve your queen！
也配不上你的王后
Prepare to feel the cold kiss of my blade…
准备好吃我一剑
Huge Ackman！
大演员
Hey，buddy，this is all pretend.
哥们 这都是演戏
See，just…
瞧见没
Well，that's not real.
那一看就不是真的
None of it is.
这全都不是真的
It's not real.
不是真的
It was a good performance.
演出不错
- We were right in there。- You were tonight.
- 我们都身临其境了 - 的确是
But it's not real-real.
但这都不是真的真的
It's not real.
都不是真的
Not real？
不是真的
Do you know how long I dreamed of Camelot？
你知道我对卡米洛特朝思暮想多久了吗
And for what？
为了什么
For nothing！
什么都不是
Jeez！
老天
Nothing！
什么都不是
No，no，no。Please just take your seats and…
别 别 都请坐下
What's up？
你们好
We're just as God made us.
我们和你一样都是上帝造的
Why don't you take a picture？
不如你拍张照片吧
It'll last longer.
照片恒久远啊
Okay，I've tried being nice。That's enough.
我一直想和气点 但你够了
Get off the stage right now！
马上从台上下去
Stay back！You don't scare me…
退后 你吓不到我
Huge Ackman.
大演员
Listen，mate，you don't want to fight me，all right？
听着 伙计 你不会想跟我单挑
If we go，I will break you.
真打起来 我打你跟玩一样
Come on！
来啊
What is that？
你这是干什么
What are you doing？
你干什么啊
He's doing his Wolverine thing.
他在出金刚狼的大招
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah。You know？
你知道的
It's better with the claws and no shirt.
得有爪子秀胸肌才有效果
Fair.
说得也是
Lancelot！
兰斯洛特
Oi，mate！
嘿 伙计
Hey，buddy，that's not an exit！
哥们 那不是出口
Yeah，come on up.
好吧 上来吧
Yep。Come on up！
行 都上来吧
Oh，monkeys。Terrific.
还有猴子 好极了
I love the costumes.
戏服不错
Sorry。I just gotta say，you're the whole package，man.
抱歉 但我得说 你是绝对的主角
Thanks，buddy.
谢谢 老兄
- He recognized you。- Yeah，that was awesome.
- 他认出你了 - 是啊 真好
Hey！Give me the Tablet！
把金碑给我
Stay back！Stay back.
退后 退后
Stand back！
别过来
Back！
退后
What？
什么
Your，uh…
你的
Your nose，it's…
你的鼻子
What about my nose？
我鼻子怎么了
Your nose is dripping.
你的鼻子要掉了
- What？- It's melting.
- 什么 - 它化了
From the fire.
因为火把
Okay.
冷静
How bad is it？
有多糟
It is not great.
不太好
But I'm Lancelot！
可我是兰斯洛特
There never was a Lancelot！
根本就没有什么兰斯洛特
Lancelot is a legend.
兰斯洛特只是个传说
You're not real.
你不是真实存在的
I don't understand！
我不明白
I know it's a lot to take in，
我知道你一时半会很难接受
but please，just give me the Tablet.
请把金碑给我吧
Oh，and then what？Back to the museum？
然后呢 回到博物馆吗
Stand there as little children ogle and point？
站在那里 让小孩子指指点点吗
And learn.
还可以学习
And get inspired to do great things.
给他们启发 让他们去做伟大的事
There are far less noble fates，my friend.
很少有人能有这么高尚的使命 朋友
Not for me，there aren't！
对我来说不一样
If there is no Camelot.
如果没有卡米洛特
There is no Guinevere and no Lancelot，
没有格温娜维尔和兰斯洛特
then I'm nothing。I'm just a sad lump of misshapen wax.
我就只是一尊畸形的蜡像
Stop looking at my nose！
别再看我的鼻子了
- I wasn't looking at it。- You were，I saw you.
- 我没在看 - 你有 我看到了
You were like this。「Hmm，hmm.」 Staring.
你很鄙视地盯着我的鼻子看
- I wasn't like that。- You were！
- 我没有 - 你有
Don't look at it！
别看它
It really is hard not to look at.
要不看真的很难
Yes，he is.
是啊
- I didn't。- I saw you！
- 我没有 - 你有
No，I'm looking at your eyes.
我只是看着你的眼睛
Monkey，stop it！
猴子 别看了
Could you give me the Tablet，please？Give me the Tablet.
把金碑给我吧 求你了
If you give me the Tablet，I promise I won't…
如果你把金碑给我 我保证我不再
Do not look at my nose！
别盯着我的鼻子看
- Give me the Tablet。- Look away.
- 把金碑给我 - 别看
- Give me the Tablet。- How hard could it be
- 把金碑给我 - 不看我的鼻子
not to look at my nose？
有那么难吗
I'm not gonna look at your nose.
我不看你的鼻子
I'm looking… I can't help it！
我 我忍不住啊
Look to the heavens！
看天空
It's disgusting.
真是太恶心了
Yet，he's still handsome.
但他还是那么帅
No one shall look at，or mention，
从这一刻开始
my nose from this moment forward！
所有人都不准看或提到我的鼻子
I'm sorry，I forgot what we were talking about.
对不起 我忘记我们说到哪里了
Lawrence.
劳伦斯
Oh，Teddy！
泰迪
Larry.
拉里
We've run out of time.
我们时间不多了
Listen to me。You got to straighten the pieces.
听我说 你必须把碎片摆正
Straighten the pieces right now or they're all gonna die！
如果你不把碎片摆正 他们都要死
You too！
你也一样
A world without Camelot is not a world worth living in.
没有卡米洛特的世界 活着也毫无意义
Dad！
爸
Dexter，what is it？
德克斯特 怎么了
You all right？
你没事吧
Hey，hey，man，you okay？
兄弟 你没事吧
Hey，look at me.
看着我
Yeah，you want to slap me？Go ahead.
你想扇我吗 来啊
Go ahead，slap me in the face.
来啊 扇我的脸啊
Dex？
小德
Dexter？
德克斯特
Oh！No，no。No.
不不不
Dexter？No，no。Come on，man！
德克斯特 快醒来啊
Dad，he's gone.
爸 它死了
I'll take that hand now.
现在我想牵你的手了
I understand now.
我终于明白了
The monkey was the quest.
一直以来使命的意义都是猴子
It was never about the Tablet.
而不是金碑
It was about them.
一切都是为了他们
Forgive me.
请原谅我
It is I who have been the fool.
原来我才是那个傻子
We're back，baby！
我们复活了 宝贝
Lawrence！
劳伦斯
Welcome back，buddy.
欢迎回来 兄弟
Well done，Larry！
干得好 拉里
There he is。That's our guy.
真棒 这才是我们的人嘛
Come here！
来
Here's your Tablet.
你的金碑
It feels good，doesn't it，Jedediah？
这感觉真好 杰迪戴亚
Boy，you said it！
那当然
Hey。Thank you.
谢谢你
How do I look？
我看起来怎样
You look like Lancelot.
你看起来像兰斯洛特
Well done，my child.
干得漂亮 孩子
Thank you…
谢谢你
for bringing my son home safely.
把我儿子安全送回来
It's a strange thing…
看着自己的孩子长大成人
seeing your boy become a man.
是一件很奇妙的事情
There were lions chasing us.
当时有很多狮子在追我们
Yeah，it's crazy.
真的很神奇
One day，they're riding a dinosaur through Central Park，
前一天才骑着恐龙穿行中央公园
and then the next day they're DJ-ing in lbiza.
第二天就在伊比沙打碟了
You've served my family well.
你竭力为我们家族效劳
We shall build a great tomb and bury you with many riches.
我们会为你建一个堆满金银财宝的墓
I，personally，will see to it that your organs are removed
我会确保 你的器官
and placed in separate jewel-encrusted jars.
被分装在塞满珠宝的罐子里
Thank you.
谢谢
Then we're agreed.
就这么定了
Lawrence，
劳伦斯
may I have a word？
能跟你聊聊吗
The others and I have been talking.
我和其他人商量了一下
Ahkmenrah's place is here with his family.
阿卡曼拉属于他的家人
He must remain here.
他必须留在这里
And the Tablet should stay here as well，son.
金碑也理应留在这里 孩子
This is where it belongs，Gigantor.
这是它的归属地 铁人
Yeah，but it…
但是
That means you guys would have to stay.
那就意味着你们也要留下了
We belong in New York.
我们属于纽约
Yeah，but if you…
但你们
If you guys go，then you，
如果你们走了 你们会
you won't be alive after tonight.
你们今晚之后就不会复活了
We're museum exhibits，Laredo.
我们是博物馆的展品 小拉里
It's what we are.
我们本来就不会动
Folks come to look at us，
大伙儿来看我们
maybe learn a little something.
也许能学到点东西
That's alive，man.
那就是活着了 兄弟
But I'm…
但我
I'm supposed to take care of you guys.
我本该照顾好你们的
And you have.
你做到了
It's okay，Lawrence.
没事的 劳伦斯
We're ready.
我们准备好了
I'm not.
可我没有
Let's go，son.
走吧 孩子
Thank you for giving me back my family，Larry.
谢谢你让我回到家人的身边 拉里
Guardian of Brooklyn.
布克林的守卫者
Dad，if we leave right now，
爸 如果我们现在出发
we can still catch a flight，
还能赶上飞机
get home with everyone still awake
趁着大家还清醒
before the sun comes up.
在太阳出来前回到家
Yeah，okay.
好吧
Let's go home.
我们回家吧
It's all right，Larry.
别紧张 拉里
We've reached something of an understanding.
我们已经达成共识了
- Really？- Trixey，sit.
- 真的吗 - 特利克西 坐下
Wow！That's really good.
不错哦
Good job，Lance.
干得漂亮 兰斯
Thanks.
谢谢
Trixey，behave.
特利克西 听话
Good girl.
好孩子
Steady.
别动
He never even listens to me.
他根本就不听我说话
But you…
但你
I just feel like you really listen to me.
我感觉你真的有听我说话
It's like our hearts are
我们的心脏
in perfect sync with each other right now.
好像在同步跳动一样
Um… Do you feel what…
你感觉到
Sorry to interrupt whatever… is happening.
抱歉 打扰了 你们的事
Uh，Laaa，the guys are waiting outside。We gotta go。Come on.
拉 大伙在外面等着呢 我们得走了
What？No.
什么 不
No！Laaa，stay！
拉 留下
I know this sounds crazy，
我知道这听起来很荒唐
but you and I could make a life together here in England.
但我们俩可以在英国好好过日子
Laaa.
拉
Wow。Okay。Um…
好吧
I will never forget you.
我永远也不会忘记你的
You are the most rugged man that I have ever，ever met.
你是我遇到过最粗犷的男人
Keep the scrunchies.
发带就留给你吧
Okay，Laaa。We gotta go.
拉 我们得走了
Come on.
走吧
I won't say anything if you won't.
你不说我也不会说的
Oh，I know you hate this job and everything，
我知道你很讨厌这份工作和这一切
but tomorrow night，
但明晚之后
best job ever.
将是最棒的工作
（自然历史博物馆）
（指令1 丢骨头）
Sure is quiet around here.
真的好安静
Without the Tablet，it's just like any other museum.
没了金碑 这里就是个普通博物馆
You know what I'm gonna remember most about you？
你知道我最想念你们什么吗
What？
什么
How big you guys are.
你们的小身板儿
Come here.
来抱抱
Hold me.
抱一下
My
我的
friend.
朋友
You speak English？
你会说英语啊
Hey，listen。Um…
听着
Up there on the roof，when…
在楼顶上的时候 当
When you almost…
当你快
Yeah.
你懂的
I just want you to know…
我只是想你知道
I really changed my perspective on everything.
我改变了我对事物的看法
I know we have a weird…
我知道我们的关系很奇怪
We have this dynamic，we have this tension.
我们时而亲近 时而疏远
Back and forth.
反复不断
I mean，games，right？You know？
我指的是 游戏 你懂吧
Roles that we put ourselves into，
我们制定了规矩
but why does it have to be that way？
可我们为什么要这样做呢
I feel like there's always been a mutual
我感觉 我们之间
sort of respect for each other.
达成了一种互相尊重的共识
Anyway，
不管怎样
I'll miss you，you know？
我会想你的 你知道吗
Okay。It's all right.
好吧 没事
Go ahead。One last slap.
来吧 最后一巴掌
Yeah，I felt that was there for a long time，too.
我也觉得我们早该亲了
Thank you.
谢谢
Who would have ever thought？
谁能想到呢
I'm wax，she's polyurethane.
我是蜡 她是聚氨酯
But somehow，it worked.
但我们却相爱了
I guess this is it.
到此为止了
Indeed.
是啊
And I know young Nick will do great things.
年轻的尼克一定会成就一番大事
Yeah，he's，uh…
他
ready to take on the world all by himself.
准备自己去迎接世界的洗礼
Then you've done your job.
你也完成了你的使命
You've done your job.
你完成了你的使命
It's time for your next adventure.
是时候开启下一段旅程了
I have no idea what I'm gonna do tomorrow.
我完全不知道自己明天要干什么
How exciting.
那多激动人心啊
Bye，Teddy.
再见 泰迪
Farewell，Lawrence.
再见 劳伦斯
Got you！
吓坏了吧
Smile，my boy.
笑一笑 孩子
It's sunrise.
太阳出来了
- Hey。- Hey。You good？
- 嘿 - 你还好吗
- Yeah，I am。- Good.
- 我很好 - 那就好
So，lbiza？
还去伊比沙吗
Yeah。Uh。The whole DJ thing，Dad，
关于当DJ的事 爸
I don't know if that's the thing for me.
我也不知道它是否适合我
I just know that it's the next thing.
我只知道它是我接下来要做的事
After that，maybe college.
在这之后 也许就上大学
I'm figuring it all out，you know？
我也还在思考未来中
Sounds like a plan.
听起来不错
I should get back to Mom's，or something.
我该回妈妈那了
Okay.
好吧
I love you.
我爱你
I love you，too.
我也爱你
All right.
抱一个
I'm not gonna let you go.
我不会放你走的
Okay。I'll see you later.
回见
（三年后）
（大英博物馆实物限时特展）
Three years，no Larry Daley.
三年了 都没见过拉里·戴利
He was the one that took the fall for me，got me my job back.
他牺牲自己 保住了我的工作
I heard he went back to school，
我听说他去读书了
got his degree，became a teacher.
拿到了学位 当了一名教师
I'm very glad.
我很为他高兴
Well，when he heard about this traveling exhibition.
当他听到这次外展之后
Larry insisted that I deliver this to you personally.
拉里让我亲自己将这个给你
Ah！The infamous，supposedly magic，glowing Tablet.
这块臭名昭著 据说会发光的魔力金碑
Larry Daley and his fanciful tales.
拉里·戴利和他的童话故事
Larry said you could be trusted.
拉里说 我可以信任你
What do you mean？
什么意思
With the top secret knowledge.
信任你能保守一个高级机密
What are you doing？
你干嘛
- I'm winking。- You're blinking.
- 我在使眼色 - 你那是眨眼
No，I wink with both eyes.
我是两只眼睛同时使眼色
That's blinking.
那就是眨眼
It doesn't matter，because right now，
那不是重点 重点是
you better get ready！
你最好给我做好准备了
For what？
准备什么
For this.
这个
It does glow.
真的发光了
Come on.
来吧
Sorry.
抱歉
Go ahead.
去吧
Have fun-fun，Dum Dum.
好好玩玩 笨笨
Stay！
留下
I'm not going anywhere.
我哪也不去
Stay！
留下
I'm not going anywhere！
我哪也不去
（大英博物馆实物限时特展）